<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Composer | Mostly Harmless]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.markbadolato.com/blog/categories/composer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.markbadolato.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-03T13:47:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.markbadolato.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Badolato]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notification When Switching to Git Branches With Different composer.lock Files]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.markbadolato.com/blog/2013/08/23/notification-when-switchin-git-branches/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-23T23:24:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.markbadolato.com/blog/2013/08/23/notification-when-switchin-git-branches</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At my office, we frequently find ourselves switching between Git branches and often we forget to run <code>composer install</code> on the new branch to make sure our vender dependencies are at the proper versions for the branch we changed to.</p>

<p>For example, <code>master</code> is stable and has an older version of a dependency, but a feature branch I&#8217;m working on uses an updated version of that dependency.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s say I&#8217;m currently working on a feature branch when a bug report comes in and I need to fix the problem ASAP. If I stash my current feature branch&#8217;s files, then create a new bug-fix branch off of master, my <code>composer.lock</code> file is different and my <code>vendor/</code> directory still contains the newer version of the dependency. This occasionally causes problems.</p>

<p>A while back I found a helpful script to use as a post-checkout Git hook. Now whenever I switch branches, I get a notification telling me my dependencies are different than the branch I just switched from.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.markbadolato.com/images/misc/branch_switch.png" /></p>

<p>To use this script on a single project, put the following in your project&#8217;s <code>.git/hooks/post-checkout</code> file (create it if it does not already exist). Make sure to set the file permissions to executable.</p>

<p>I prefer to keep the script in my global <code>git-core/templates/hooks/post-checkout</code> file so it&#8217;s accessible for all of my projects. <strong>Tip:</strong> After installing the file, run <code>git init</code> in an existing project to update the hooks and bring the global file down locally to your project.</p>

<pre><code class="bash /usr/local/share/git-core/templates/hooks/post-checkout">#!/bin/bash

PREV_COMMIT=$1
POST_COMMIT=$2

NOCOLOR='\x1B[0m'
REDCOLOR='\x1B[37;41m'

if [[ -f composer.lock ]]; then
    DIFF=`git diff --shortstat $PREV_COMMIT..$POST_COMMIT composer.lock`
    if [[ $DIFF != "" ]]; then
        echo -e "$REDCOLOR composer.lock has changed. You must run composer install$NOCOLOR"
    fi
fi
</code></pre>

<p><em>Please note: This script is modified to properly display color codes on a Mac/BSD system. If you&#8217;re on Linux and having display issues, change the instances of <code>\x1B</code> to <code>\e</code> and it will work for you.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
